The horror continues…
The Night Strangler is a tv movie, horror, mystery film directed by Dan Curtis.
After being run out of Las Vegas, reporter Carl Kolchak heads for
Seattle and another reporting job with the local paper.
It's not long before he’s on the trail of another string of bizarre murders.
It seems that every 21 years, for the past century, a killer murders a certain number of
people, drains them of their blood, and then disappears into the night.
Kolchak is on his trail, but can he stop him?
Carl Kolchak, played by Darren McGavin.
Louise Harper, played by Jo Ann Pflug.
Tony Vincenzo, played by Simon Oakland.
Capt. Schubert, played by Scott Brady.
Mr. Berry, played by Wally Cox.
Prof. Crabwell, played by Margaret Hamilton.
The Night Strangler is an American made-for-television horror film that first
aired on ABC on January 16, 1973, as a sequel to The Night Stalker.
In the film, Carl Kolchak (played by Darren McGavin), an investigative reporter assigned to series
of killings, comes to suspect the murderer is an immortal with superhuman strength.
The Night Strangler, though not as popular as its predecessor, garnered both strong ratings and
positive reviews, eventually prompting ABC to order a TV series Kolchak: The Night Stalker.
Neither writer Richard Matheson nor producer/director
Dan Curtis was involved in the TV series.
In the United States, the TV movie ran (without
commercials) approximately 74 minutes.
ABC planned to release the film overseas as a theatrical release and had
additional footage shot, rounding out the movie to 90 minutes.
The film explores themes of sequel, investigative journalist, occult detective.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.